Özer Özdal

Contact Information

Tel: +1 438 935 74 64 ozerozdal@gmail.com linkedin://ozerozdal github://oozdal

Personal Information

•Date of birth 28/05/1990 •Place of birth Izmir, Turkey

Languages

Native Turkish Advanced English French (A2 Level)

Software Skills

Monte Carlo Sampling
Statistical Modeling
Linear regression
Clustering
Quantitative Analysis
Data Visualization

Coursework •Machine Learning

Deep Learning

Specialization
•SQL for Data Science
•Linear Algebra
•Multivariate Calculus
•Probability Theory
•Computational Physics
•Classical Mechanics
•Quantum Mechanics
•Statistical Mechanics

Tools

PYTHON, C++ SQL, FORTRAN CERN ROOT, LaTeX Bash shell scripting MATHEMATICA, MATLAB

Packages

Scikit-Learn, NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Pytorch, TensorFlow

Data Science Experience

since 2018 **Machine Learning in High-Energy Physics**My goal is to compare two D dimensional samples: the SM simulated events (background to BSM searches), and the real data, and to check if the two are drawn from the same probability density distribution.

Education

2016–2020 **Ph.D. in Theoretical High Energy Physics**Concordia University
Phenomenology of new physics beyond the Standard Model: signals of dark
matter and new gauge bosons at colliders. Lead to five scientific publications.

2016–2017 Inter-University Transfer Student
Took two graduate courses: Quantum Field Theory I - II

2014–2016 M.Sc. in Theoretical High Energy Physics Izmir Institute of Technology
The Higgs boson and right-handed neutrinos in supersymmetric models.

Lead to two scientific publications.

2009–2014 **B.Sc. in Physics (Ranked 3rd)** Izmir Institute of Technology Revisited N-symmetric barrier tunneling in Quantum Mechanics

Experience

2016–2020 Research Assistant (RA) Concordia University
 Mariana Frank Research Group
 2019-2020 Visiting Ph.D. Student Next Institute & University of Southampton
 Supported by MITACS Globalink Research Award. Lead to two scientific
 publications.
 2016-2020 Teaching Assistant (TA)

TAed for 8 physics courses. Graded assignments and wrote solutions, lead office hours and tutorial sessions.

2015–2016 Research Assistant (RA)

Studied muon anomalous magnetic moment and yukawa quasi-unification in supersymmetric Models. Lead to two scientific publications.

2012–2012 Internship

Koc University. Mechanical Characterization Lab

Internship Koç University, Mechanical Characterization Lab
Created vibration modeling in nanowire resonators with mechanical coupling

Relevant Accomplishments

- 7 peer-reviewed scientific publications in High Energy Physics
- · Gave 17 talks about my research at conferences
- Awarded Globalink Research Award by MITACS and Graduate Student Mobility Award by Concordia University
- · Attended 18 scientific workshops, summer/winter schools in top institutions
- · Awarded by Concordia International Tuition Award of Excellence
- · B.Sc. in Physics 3rd Ranked Award